

SAAD BARADAN

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

720-341-9511

https://www.linkedin.com/in/saad-baradan

Git

https://github.com/saadricklamar

SKILLS

Languages/Frameworks

- JavaScript
- HTML5
- CSS3
- React
- Redux
- React Native
- Vue.js
- Node.js/Express
- PostgreSQL/Knex
- NativeScript
- jQuery
- Jest/Enzyme

Tools

- Git/Github
- Linux
- Jira
- Postman
- Heroku
- Travis CI
- Figma/Adobe
- pgAdmin

EDUCATION

Turing School of Software & Design, Front-End Engineering Jan 2019 - Aug 2019

Colorado State University, M.A. Philosophy

Sept 2013 - May 2015

University of Colorado Denver, B.A. Philosophy

June 2007 - May 2011

SUMMARY

I am a Software Engineer with a passion for Front End Technologies. I enjoy practicing agile development, putting together thoughtful and intuitive UIs, and collaborating with colleagues and clients to enhance our products and user experiences.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer - Frontend, Loyal Health

January 2022 - Present

• Details coming soon...

Delivery Software Engineer, IQGeo

January 2020 - January 2022

- Utilize JavaScript, HTML5/CSS3, & React to enhance GUIs and build out new Front End features
- Use UX/UI tools such as Adobe and Figma to create various design documents in collaboration with clients
- Utilize Python & PostgreSQL to bring in new data and enhance Back End functionality
- Use Linux to develop, test, and deploy software to various environments (QA, STG, & PROD)
- Use FogBugz & Jira to track, troubleshoot, and resolve bugs for clients in a timely manner
- Implement new installs of myWorld and other IQGeo products for clients
- Collaborate remotely with colleagues across US and international timezones

Projects

My Portfolio - https://find-saad.herokuapp.com/

My portfolio website highlighting my projects, photography, and more.

Tech Used: JavaScript, HTML5/CSS3, React, React Scroll, EmailJS, Jest/Enzyme, Cypress, Heroku